VADYM LOTAR

(0151) 2555 80 42

vadim.lot@gmail.com

www.facebook.com/vadim.lot

During my career I've been a key person on several startups as well as on a big enterprise project working for HP. I have strong technical, management and self-management skills. Being a good team player and mentor I'm trying to boost team performance and improve the quality at any project I'm working on.

DEVELOPMENT MANAGER / SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

PROFFESIONAL SUMMARY

Working in commercial organizations since 2007, I took over different positions and responsibilities such as R&D Software Engineer, Team Lead and Architect. I was mainly focusing on designing and developing software systems using Micro-Service architecture. Leading an international distributed team, I was able to build a very strong department within the organization. Being keen on innovations and new technologies, I always try to build flexible and maintainable solutions minimizing effort and risks.

SKILLS

- Programming languages: Java, JavaScript
- Databases: MySQL, MSSQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL
- NoSQL: Cassandra, Redis
- Other: Spring Framework, Spring Boot/Cloud, Hibernate, iBatis, JSF (IceFaces), SOLR, ELK, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Docker, Kubernetes

EXPERIENCE

adidas AG, Herzogenaurach, Germany

Sr. Solution Architect, 2017 – present Projects: core platform components. Responsibilities: Design, Software Development, Technical Consultancy

RAKUTEN DEUTSCHLAND GmbH, Bamberg, Germany

Team Lead/Software Architect, 2013 – 2017 Projects: Checkout, Search, CSV Import Service, Campaign Platform, Review API, etc.

Responsibilities: Leader of distributed team (10-14 engineers). Platform architect and main contributor responsible for the whole application lifecycle. Organizer of internal EU Rakuten Tech Talks.

LOHIKA INC (HP), Odessa, UKR

Senior R&D Software Engineer/Tech Advocate, 2011 - 2013

Project: Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) Responsibilities: Design and implementation of software modules, mentoring, speaker in training center and on Java conferences, technical leader, interviewer.

INTERSOG LTD, Odessa, UKR

Software Engineer, 2007 - 2011

Projects: IPSCO TMS, Tenaris TMS, Mitsubishi Motors Canada Steel Resale application. Responsibilities: Requirements analysis and component/feature development, mentoring.

EDUCATION

Polytechnic University

Odessa, Ukraine Master Degree in Computer Science - 2010

LANGUAGES

English – Full professional proficiency

Russian - Native

Ukrainian - Native

German – Limited professional proficiency (B1)